[
  {
    "id": "0",
    "question": "Who developed Kotlin?",
    "optionA": "IBM",
    "optionB": "GOOGLE",
    "optionC": "JetBrains",
    "optionD": "Microsoft",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "Which extension is responsible to save Kotlin files ?",
    "optionA": ".kot",
    "optionB": ".android",
    "optionC": ".src",
    "optionD": ".kt or .kts",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "The two types of constructors in Kotlin are ?",
    "optionA": "Primary and Secondary constructor",
    "optionB": "First and the second constructor",
    "optionC": "Constant and Parameterized constructor",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "correctAnswer": "0",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "What handles null exceptions in Kotlin ?",
    "optionA": "Sealed classes",
    "optionB": "Lambda functions",
    "optionC": "The Kotlin extension",
    "optionD": "Elvis operator",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "question": "The correct function to get the length of a string in Kotlin language is ??",
    "optionA": "str.length",
    "optionB": "string(length)",
    "optionC": "lengthof(str)",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "correctAnswer": "0",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": " The function to print a line in Kotlin is ?",
    "optionA": "Printline()",
    "optionB": "println()",
    "optionC": "print()",
    "optionD": "option (b) and (c)",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "In Kotlin",
    "optionA": " the default visibility modifier is ?sealed",
    "optionB": "public",
    "optionC": "protected",
    "optionD": "private",
    "correctAnswer": "1",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": " What defines a sealed class in Kotlin ??",
    "optionA": "Its another name for an abstract class",
    "optionB": "It represents restricted class hierarchies",
    "optionC": "It is used in every Kotlin program",
    "optionD": "None of above",
    "correctAnswer": "1",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": " The default behavior of classes in Kotlin is ?",
    "optionA": "All classes are protected",
    "optionB": "All classes are sealed",
    "optionC": "All classes are final",
    "optionD": "All classes are public",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "The functions in Kotlin can be divided into how many types ?",
    "optionA": "5",
    "optionB": "4",
    "optionC": "3",
    "optionD": "2",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "What are the most important benefit/benefits of using Kotlin language ?",
    "optionA": "It is is a functional language and based on Java Virtual Machine",
    "optionB": "It is an expressive language that makes code readable and understandable",
    "optionC": "It is an expressive language that makes code readable and understandable",
    "optionD": "All of the above",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "Which are the basic data types in Kotlin ?",
    "optionA": "Arrays and Booleans",
    "optionB": "Characters",
    "optionC": "Strings and Numbers",
    "optionD": "All of these",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "Which of these features are available in Kotlin but not in the Java language ?",
    "optionA": "Operator overloading",
    "optionB": "Coroutines and Null safety",
    "optionC": "Range expressions",
    "optionD": "All of the above",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "s Kotlin really better than Java?",
    "optionA": "No,Java is better",
    "optionB": "Both have similar functionalities",
    "optionC": "Yes , Kotlin is really better",
    "optionD": "Some features in Java are better than Kotlin",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "userAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "question": "val short for Value",
    "optionA": "It can be changed but once only",
    "optionB": "It can be changed",
    "optionC": "val cannot be changed after its assigned",
    "optionD": "Both (a) and (b)",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "userAnswer": ""
  }
]